## **ANJA SHEPPARD**

2801 Rutford Avenue Box #8, Richardson, TX, 75080 ams180001@utdallas.edu (919) 619-7597

September 20th, 2018 Hiring Manager's Name

300 Riverpark Dr. North Reading, MA 01864

Dear Hiring Manager,

Hello! My name is Anja Sheppard. I am excited to apply to the Software Development Internship position at Amazon Robotics for the upcoming summer. As an enthusiastic learner with experience in robotics and programming, I believe I am the right candidate for the job.

I am a current freshman at the University of Texas at Dallas as a McDermott Scholar. I have accumulated years of experience in robotics and programming through extracurricular projects and an internship at the Shodor Education Foundation. These opportunities have taught me important skills in C++, C, database management, and Robot Operating System (ROS), as well as professionalism, time management, and teamwork.

Aside from my technical experience, I also strive to create the ideal work environment wherever I go. I have achieved organizational success by focusing on a flat leadership structure. Fully committing to each individual in a team setting has helped me form relationships with co-workers and more efficiently reach goals.

I consider myself a unique hire, and hope that after reviewing my resume, you will too! I would love to elaborate on my specific skill set and how it will be beneficial to Amazon Robotics. Please contact me at (919) 619-7597 or at ams180001@utdallas.edu.

Thank you for your consideration, and I look forward to hearing back from you soon.

Sincerely, Anja Sheppard

## **ANJA SHEPPARD**

2801 Rutford Avenue Box #8, Richardson, TX, 75080 ams180001@utdallas.edu (919) 619-7597

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Ambitious student seeking meaningful full-time summer internship. As a naturally quick learner, I am eager to contribute to Amazon Robotics through my knowledge in computer vision, automation, and ROS.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Speaker at ROSConference in Madrid, Spain NCSSM Rocketry Captain

September 2018

2016 - 2018

- Lead team through NASA high-powered rocketry competition for first time in school history
- Program and build electronics for the Landing Site Estimator scientific payload

#### **Software Intern at Shodor Education Foundation**

2015 - 2018

- Designed a programming concepts curriculum to teach JavaScript to Durham minority students
- Collaborated on converting Modeling and Simulation Tools for Education Reform (MASTER) Tools Sim-Surface and Galaxsee into JavaScript web applications

## **FIRST Robotics Competition Lead Programmer**

2014 - 2018

• Improved and maintained Team 900 code base in computer vision, sensor fusion, and Simultaneous Localization and Mapping (SLAM)

#### RESEARCH

### **NCSSM Mentorship Research Program**

February 2017 - February 2018

 Organized and designed research project on "Global Map Recognition and Path Planning on the Nao Humanoid Robot" using the A\* (A star) algorithm with Mr. Kyle Snyder at the NextGen Air Transporation Consortium at NC State University

#### **Beaver Works Summer Institute**

July 2017 - August 2017

• Developed drone software to fly autonomously through a course after learning about control systems and sensors at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

McDermott Scholar at the University of Texas at Dallas Girl Scout Gold Award

2018 - present

2016

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Texas at Dallas

August 2018 - May 2022

# North Carolina School of Science and Mathematics

August 2016 - May 2018

Weighted GPA: 5.52 Unweighted GPA: 3.97

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: Python, C, C++, Robot Operating System (ROS), LATEX, Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Ruby, MySQL
- Operating Systems: Linux, macOS
- Languages: German, French